dnslytics.com 2019-12-02

# Privacy Policy for DNSlytics

Through its online service, DNSlytics will process privacy-sensitive or personal data. Webdevmedia values the privacy of its customers and observes due care in processing and protecting personal data. We process data in compliance with the requirements laid down by the Dutch Personal Data Protection Act (DPDA). Webdevmedia is the party responsible for all data processing. In this privacy statement, we will explain which personal data we collect and for which purposes. We recommend that you read it carefully.

This privacy statement was last amended on 2018-05-24.

## Data collected on our website

**Use of Personal Data**

By using our website, you are providing certain data to us. This could be personal data. We only retain and use the personal data provided directly by you or for which it is clear that it has been supplied to us to be processed. We use the following data for the purposes mentioned below:  
\- Name and address  
\- Billing address  
\- Email address  
\- Payment details  
\- IP address

 **Registration**

Certain features of our service require you to register beforehand. After your registration we will retain your user name and the personal data you provided. We will retain this data so that you do not have to re-enter it every time you visit our website, to contact you in connection with the execution of the agreement, invoicing and payment, and to provide an overview of the products and services you have purchased from us.

We will not provide the data linked to your user name to third parties, unless it is necessary for the execution of the agreement you concluded with us or if this is required by law. In the event of suspicion of fraud or misuse of our website we may hand over personal data to the entitled authorities.

**Handling your order**

We will use your personal data when handling your order. If necessary for proper handling, we can provide your data to third parties. We will explain this in detail later.

 **Newsletter**

We have a newsletter to inform those interested of our products and/or services. Each newsletter contains a link with which to unsubscribe from our newsletter. Your email address will be added to the list of subscribers only with your explicit consent.

**Contact and Support Form**

If you fill out a contact or support form on the website or send us an email, the data you provide will be retained for as long as is necessary depending on the nature of the form or the content of your email, to fully answer and correctly handle your message or email.

**Webserver logs**

Our webserver logs your IP address, webpage visited, internet browser and timestamp. This data is only used to prevent abuse of our service and is deleted after 180 days.

**Providing Data to Third Parties**

We may provide your data to our partners. These partners are involved in the execution of the agreement. These partners may be based outside the EU. However, they make use of the European model clauses. Such third party parties may include:  
\- Hosting Providers, technical partners hosting and securing the website, sending emails and store our data.  
\- Payment Providers, financial partners handling fraud detection, payments and subscriptions.  
\- SaaS Providers, online software partners providing accounting, email and CRM functionality.

**Advertisements**

Our service displays advertisements of third parties, who keep personal data to personalise these. Starting from 25 May 2018 only non-personalized ads are displayed to users in the European Economic Area (EEA). Non-personalized ads do not collect any personal data and are targeted using contextual information rather than the past behavior of a user.

**Google Analytics**

We use Google Analytics to track visitors on our website and to get reports about how visitors use the website. We accepted the data processing agreement from Google. We don't allow Google to use information obtained by Analytics for other Google services, and we anonymize the IP adresses.

 **Security**

We take security measures to reduce misuse of and unauthorised access to personal data. We take the following measures in particular:  
\- Access to personal data requires the use of a user name and password.  
\- All personal data is stored inside the European Union (EU).  
\- We make use of secure connections (Secure Sockets Layer of SSL) to encrypt all information between you and our website when entering your personal data.

**Third-party Websites**

This statement is not applicable to third-party websites connected to this website through links. We cannot guarantee that these third parties will handle your personal data in a secure and careful manner. We recommend you read these websites’privacy statements before making use of these websites.

 **Inspection and Modification of your Data**

You can always contact us if wish to review, modify or delete your personal data.

**Data collected**

Our browser addons, extensions and apps (hereafter called "addon") do not embed any kind of tracking or analytic code. All the information displayed by the addon is collected by our service. The addon sends a request to our service for information. Your IP address, internet browser and timestamp will be logged for every request. We only use this information to protect our service for abuse. These logs are removed after 180 days. Depending on the function of the addon this request may include the hostname part of the current URL. The first time we detect a new hostname it will be added to our database of hostnames and used to deliver our tools and services. Collected hostname data is always stored without any user context or reference to personally identifiable information.

**Advertisements**

Ads may be displayed inside our addon. Ads consists of text links or images hosted on our own server. We do not use any cookie, iframe or other techniques to track users. By clicking on an advertisement you are redirected to a third-party website. This privacy policy does not apply to these websites and we cannot control there activities.

All data we collect and process is publicly available on the internet. We can not collect protected data and we do not bypass any security measures. Below we describe the data we collect and the measures we are taking to minimize the collection and use of personal data.

**DNS, Domain and server IP data**

For our DNS investigation services we collect several DNS, domain names and server IP records. This data is for example used to track spammers or hackers, detect potentially fraudulent transactions, identify malicious websites and to protect intellectual property. To collect domain names we use the official published zone files, hostnames collected by our addons and public sources like commoncrawl.org. To collect DNS and server IP records we use a technique called active DNS. Active DNS means our system queries the DNS server to collect the data. We do not use any user input or user logs. By using the active DNS technique all data is collected and stored without any user context or reference to personally identifiable information. The data we collect are:  
\- A, AAAA, MX, NS and SPF records for every domain name.  
\- A and AAAA records for every mail (MX record) and name server (NS record).  
\- A and AAAA records for every subdomain.

**Website data**

Our service crawls all active domains and hostnames. We only fetch the homepage and the ads.txt and robots.txt files. To avoid the collection of personal data we do not store the content of the homepage. We only extract and collect technical and meta data from it. The data we collect are: name and version of the webserver, HTTP headers, HTML meta tags, Adsense ID, Google Analytics ID, technology frameworks used, script and CSS files used. We use this data to generate reports. For example a report of domains using a certain webserver.

**Whois data**

On our service whois data is displayed. Whois data may contain personal data. Starting from 25 May 2018 most domain registrars removed the personal data of EU companies and individuals. The whois data is shown for the sole purpose of assisting our users in obtaining information about domain name or IP address registration records and for no other purpose. We only serve this data to the user who made the request. For performance reasons we cache this data for a limited time. After the cache has expired the whois data is deleted from our systems. We have implemented the following measures to protect against misuse of the whois data:  
\- We do not offer bulk access to whois data.  
\- We do not offer any services based on whois data like whois history or reverse whois.  
\- Email addresses and fax/phone numbers are displayed as images to protect against abuse and spam.

We reserve the right to modify this statement. We recommend that you review this statement regularly, so that you remain informed of any changes.
